TheChaosLegion
l want to shine on you,
and always like that dazzling sun.
l will defend you
from all the darkness.
This is the truth from my heart.
lf only our hearts could connect,
l could get you to believe me.
Even if you can't
see it now, don't lose it.
Your kindness won't be in vain.
You'll be carried aloft by the wind
to somewhere that isn't here.
You'll cross the sea and cross time,
and l know you'll blossom one day.
Whatever the day,
l'll be there for you.
l hope l can watch over you
like the sun for all time.
This is the truth from my heart.
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
～♪
l've waited for two years, and we
haven't had the chance to talk yet!
（タンダ）２年待って 俺はまだ
お前と話もしてねえんだぞ
バルサ
Episode 4
Torogai's
Letter
Wait! Stay a little longer!
（トロガイ）待て！ もう少し…
ブハッ
ハァ ハァ ハァ
Damn, it was too far away!
クソ！ 遠すぎた
こっちは
１か月近く待ったんだから―
l waited for nearly a month.
Couldn't the Water Folk hang on a bit?
水の民も もうちょいと
我慢してくれりゃいいものを…
やっぱり結び目じゃないと
まともに会話はできんか
Perhaps proper communication
isn't possible unless l'm at the Knot.
Looks like the second prince
didn't die in that fire after all.
どうやら第二皇子は
あの火事で死んじゃいないようだが
Still, l wonder what he meant by that?
しかし あれは
どういう意味なんだろうねえ
うん？ 卵！
An egg?
So, a being from Nayug laid an egg
here in this world, eh?
ナユグの者が
こっちの世界に卵を産んだってか？
こいつは
早々に結び目に行って―
l have to go to the Knot right away
and talk to the Water Folk again.
もう一度 水の民に
話を聞かないといけないね
しかし こんな機会が
生きているうちに訪れるとは…
l never dreamed a chance like this
would present itself in my lifetime.
What l wouldn't give to see that egg
with my own two eyes!
ぜひとも その卵を
この目で拝んでみたいもんだね
But first of all, l suppose l should
get rid of those pesky pups!
その前に うっとうしい犬っころを
始末しておくか
But l guess l can't do that.
だが そうもいかんか
あの聖導師(せいどうし)のクソガキに―
l couldn't live with
myself if l didn't give...
ひと言 言ってやらんと
気が済まんしな
...that cheeky brat of a
master star reader a piece of my mind.
Hey! Come down here!
おい！ 下りてきな！
陰気くさい犬っころだね
You're a dour-looking
pair of pups, aren't you?
You'd do well to remember this.
覚えときな キレイな花には
毒香(どっか)があるってことをね
The more beautiful the flower,
the deadlier its fragrance.
They don't always send you off
to a pleasant sleep.
いい夢ばっかりは
見せちゃくれないよ
You make sure that this message
gets delivered, you stupid pups.
しっかり便りを届けんだよ
この犬っころめが
This is Shuga, who will be
serving Your Majesty in secret.
（聖導師）これより
帝(みかど)の陰にお仕えいたします―
シュガにございます
He is rather young, is he not?
（帝）ずいぶんと若いな
lndeed. He is the youngest
star reader in history...
（聖導師）はい
歴代最年少の星読み博士であり―
先日まで
二ノ宮(にのみや)のカシヅキをしておりました
...and until recently, was
tutor-governor of Ninomiya Palace.
（帝）それほどの才か
He is that talented, then?
Shuga, in view of your talents,
you may serve in my shadow.
シュガよ その才をもって
余の陰に入ることを許す
（シュガ）より精進に励みます
l shall redouble all of my efforts, Sire.
（帝）狩人の首尾は どうじゃ？
And what of the Hunters' pursuit?
（聖導師）失敗いたしました
They have failed.
（帝）失敗したと？
（聖導師）はい
Failed, you say?
Yes, Sire.
This is unprecedented.
Failing to carry out my command...
生まれて初めてじゃな
余の命が遂げられなかったのは
Was this female bodyguard
truly that formidable?
それほどに手ごわかったか？
その女用心棒とやらは
Or perhaps they were under
the water demon's protection.
とはいえ―
水妖(すいよう)の加護があったと
考えるべきなのかもしれんな
（聖導師）仰せのとおりかと
l believe that may be the case, Sire.
However, while this woman
may have driven the Hunters away.
しかし その女
狩人を退けたとはいえ―
l am told that she was
gravely injured in the process.
相当の深手を負ったとのこと
となれば
そう遠くへは行けますまい
That being the case, it is unlikely
that she could have gone far.
Grant me leave to dispatch
the remaining Hunters, and surely...
早々に残りの狩人を放ち 必ずや…
How many Hunters are still
able to perform their duties?
動ける狩人は 何人残っておる？
lncluding myself, there are five, Sire.
（モン）私を含め５名
ふむ
ln that case, let us
try another method.
では 別の方法でいこう
Sire?
As soon as Chagum's
viewing ceremonies are completed...
チャグムの拝訣(はいけつ)の儀が終わりしだい
弔いの山狩りを催せ
...conduct a manhunt
to appease his spirit.
We shall dispatch troops
who know nothing.
事情を知らせぬ兵を 放火の
下手人の捜索と称して放つのだ
Mobilize them under the pretext
of searching for the arsonist.
その折 モンよ
お前たちは影を行け
Mon, that will be your cover
to operate in secret.
Yes, Sire!
Preparations to place the body
in the coffin seem to be proceeding.
（ガカイ）お舟入りの準備が
進んでいるようですな
（サグム）チャグムの遺体は
見つからなかったと聞く
l am told that Chagum's body
was never found.
なのに お舟入りとはな
And yet, they are still
preparing a coffin.
本当にチャグムは死んだのか？
ls Chagum really dead?
Body or no body, the second prince
has indeed passed away.
ご遺体がなくとも 第二皇子が
お隠れになったのは事実です
Then why has the second queen
been moved to the lnner Palace?
では なぜに 二ノ妃(にのきさき)を
奥ノ宮(おくのみや)に移すなどしたのだ？
本当にチャグムが死んだというのなら
あまりの仕打ちではないか！
lf Chagum is indeed dead,
surely that is cruel treatment!
ゆくゆくは この国を治める
帝になられる お方が―
One who will eventually
rule this country...
そのような 些事(さじ)に
とらわれてはいけません
...ought not concern himself
with such trivial matters.
ls it trivial to show concern for
the mother of my younger brother?
弟の母君の心配をすることが
些事だと申すか？
lf so, then one must truly be
cold of heart to be mikado.
だとすれば帝とは それほどに
心冷たくあらねばならぬのだな
lt is for that reason that l wanted
Chagum to live in a world...
であればこそ チャグムには―
そのような冷たさとは
無縁の世界に生きてほしかった
...devoid of such callousness.
Simply watching Chagum
running and playing happily...
チャグムが元気に
走り回る姿を見ているだけで―
余は幸せな気分になれたものを…
...raised my spirits to no end.
（聖導師）無人の体(てい)にて
Become empty vessels.
What is it this time?
今度は何だ？
We have received an unusual letter
from the magic weaver.
かの呪術師めから
怪しげな文が届きました
よもや 呪術師を追った者までもが
しくじったか
Surely those who pursued the
magic weaver did not fail me as well.
して その文とは？
So what is this letter?
（モン）これに
Here it is.
なるほど
Ah, l see.
モンよ わしは済んだことを
どうこう言うつもりはない
Mon, l don't intend to dwell on
what is over and done with.
There is no shortage of matters that
you and your men must attend to.
そちたちがすべきことは
山積しておる
今は傷を癒やし 次なる命に備えよ
For now, heal your wounds and
be ready for your next orders.
Sir!
（聖導師）
読んでみよ そなた宛でもある
Read it. lt is addressed to you as well.
To my dear star readers...
（シュガ）“星を見ず
足元に うつつを抜かす聖導師よ”
...who, rather than gaze at the stars,
instead fix their gaze on their feet.
“二ノ宮の身内に宿りしもの
しかと見極めねば―”
lgnoring the nature of the being
that resides in the second prince...
...will result in a terrible
drought afflicting this land.
“恐ろしい乾きが
この地を襲うであろう”
Your ancestors had the capacity
to work for a common cause.
“なんじらの祖は 我らと
たもとを連ねるだけの度量あり”
Though it pains me to say so,
we Yakoo have also...
“だが 口惜しきか―”
“我らヤクーも
時のかなたに大事を置き忘れり”
...misplaced something vital
in the depths of time.
l shall now go forth to visit one
who knows the truth of this matter.
“これより 我
真実を知る者を訪ねん”
“我 戻るまで
なんじら 浅慮な行いは慎むべし”
Until l return, l suggest you refrain
from taking any rash action.
How do you interpret this letter?
この文 どう読む？
Torogai is already aware of
the sign of the great drought...
トロガイ師は
乾ノ相(かわきのそう)をすでに承知しており―
...and is about to undertake an
investigation to further study its cause.
しかも その原因について―
さらなる調べを行う手だても
持っている―
ということのようですね
That is how l interpret it.
（聖導師）うむ
Master, l believe we should work
with the Yakoo magic weavers...
聖導師様 ここは
ヤクーの呪術師と手を組み―
...and conduct an exchange
of knowledge with them.
お互いの知識を共有するべきかと
知識を共有？
Exchange knowledge with them?
Reveal all to the magic weavers?
The very thought is outrageous!
我らの持つ知識を
呪術師に漏らすなど言語道断
Star readers must never go to
magic weavers in search of advice!
まして星読みが 呪術師に
教えを請うなどあってはならんのだ
But they are more knowledgeable on...
ですが 優位性はあちらに…
（聖導師）この一件には―
But they are more knowledgeable on...
Do not forget...
我ら新ヨゴ皇国の威信が
懸かっておるということを忘れるな
...that the honor of Shin-Yogo
hangs in the balance.
Nevertheless, l do not suggest that
we attempt to slay the prince...
だが やみくもに 水妖がつきし
皇子を成敗しようとは―
...and the water demon
that possesses him.
わしも考えてはおらん
この星ノ宮(ほしのみや)には―
Here in the Star Palace...
...there is a storehouse which only
the master star readers know of.
聖導師になった者しか知らぬ
秘密の倉がある
そこには 建国の立て役者―
ln that room lie epistles left behind
by grand master star reader Nanai...
ナナイ大聖導師が残した碑文が
眠っておる
...who played such a pivotal role
in the founding of the country.
However, being written in
the ancient Yogo tongue...
しかし その碑文は
古代ヨゴ文字で書かれており―
...deciphering them all will take
considerable time and effort.
全てを読み解くには
かなりの手間と時間がかかる
Shuga, you are hereby relieved
of your duties as star reader.
シュガよ このときより
そなたの星読みの任を解く
近く 我が国を襲うであろう
大干ばつを防ぐためにも―
To prevent the drought likely to befall
our country in the near future...
...l charge you with the task
of deciphering the epistles.
そなたに碑文解読の任を与える
Decipher the epistles
and find a means...
呪術師トロガイより先に
水妖を確実に 屠(ほふ)る術を―
...of vanquishing the water demon
before the magic weaver does.
碑文から読み解くのだ
水妖を屠る…
A way to vanquish the water demon...
l am honored to accept this task
of deciphering the epistles.
碑文解読の任
謹んで お受けいたします
（聖導師）
解読結果は全て わしに報告せよ
Report to me everything
that you uncover.
l have every faith in you.
期待しているぞ
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
Well, l've managed to patch you up...
（タンダ）なんとか処置はしたが…
What in the world
happened to you, Balsa?
いったい何があったんだ？ バルサ
Tanda!
（トーヤ）タンダ！
（タンダ）うん？
（タンダ）うん なるほど
Now l understand.
l'm sorry. l can't do anything right.
（トーヤ）すまねえ
俺が下手打ったばっかりに
Don't be so hard on yourself.
lt isn't your fault.
気に病むな お前のせいじゃない
こいつが
むちゃしすぎるからいけないのさ
lt's her own fault for
being so reckless.
Still, going by what you've told me...
にしても
お前の話から察するに―
この子は 二ノ宮の
皇子様ってことになりそうだな
...l suppose that would make this boy
the prince of Ninomiya Palace.
（バルサ）ジグロ！ うっ
Jiguro?
（バルサ）
あんた なんで ここにいるんだい？
You?
What are you doing here?
あっ… どのぐらい寝てた？
How long have l been unconscious?
lt hasn't even been a full day yet.
まだ １日も たってねえよ
A day?
１日…
タンダ 私が倒れていた場所で
人の気配はなかったかい？
Tanda, did you sense anyone
around where you found me?
お前の足跡と血の跡しかなかったよ
All l saw there were your footprints
and drops of your blood.
そうか
Oh...
l've heard about your situation.
You should really thank these two.
事情は聞いた
こいつらに感謝しろよ
トーヤ ありがとよ
Toya...thanks.
タンダ
この子に何か起こらなかったかい？
Tanda, did anything
happen to the boy?
Not really.
別に
More importantly, is he really...
それより この子…
l didn't want to get you involved in all this.
あんたを
巻き込みたくなかったんだけどね
お察しのとおり この子は
新ヨゴ皇国の第二皇子だよ
As you've probably guessed,
he's Shin-Yogo's second prince.
名前はチャグム
His name is Chagum.
つきものに
取りつかれちまったばかりに―
Because he's been
possessed by a spirit...
...the Mikado considers him tainted
and has ordered him to be killed.
汚れを嫌った帝に
殺されそうになったんだ
それで 二ノ妃に
用心棒を頼まれちまってね
And that's why the second queen
hired me as his bodyguard.
And this is the outcome.
この ありさまさ
まったく お前ってヤツは…
You're really hopeless!
Look, l want to help him
as much as the next person, but...
まあ 俺だって
助けてやりたいとは思うだろうがさ
Tanda, l want you to
find out what that spirit is.
タンダ あんたに その つきものが
何なのか見てほしいんだ
lf possible, l'd like you to
remove it from him.
可能なら
その つきものを落としてほしい
A spirit, you say? l don't know...
つきものったってなあ…
Your master's the only one
who can handle it, then?
やっぱり
師匠じゃなきゃ無理かい？
無理ってことはないが…
l didn't say that l couldn't do it!
どれ ちょいと見せてみな
Here, let me take a quick look.
何だい？
What is it?
（タンダ）俺には
ちょっと手に負えない感じだな
l have a feeling that
l'm in over my head here.
そうか
l see.
But it seems to be something
that came from Nayug.
だけど
こいつは ナユグのもののようだ
Meaning we'll need to have
Torogai take a look, after all.
となると やっぱり
トロガイ師に見せたいところだね
Yes, but she's out drifting
wherever the wind takes her again.
だが相変わらず
風の吹くままだからなあ
You're right...
そうだね
タンダ
（タンダ）うん？
Tanda.
Do you have any food
that will help me recover?
何か精のつく食い物ないか？
あんまり猶予もないんだ
There's no time to spare.
How long will it take
this wound to heal?
この傷 どのぐらいで治ると思う？
ふざけるなよ
Don't be ridiculous.
lt'll take even you ten days.
いくらお前でも10日
ひいき目に見ても７日はかかる
Seven if we're being optimistic...
l can't wait that long.
そんなに待てないんだよ
They might be at
our throats any minute.
いつ追っ手が来るかも
分からないんだ
Please do something!
なんとかしておくれ
あんたたちにも
これ以上 迷惑は かけられない
l can't bear to cause you
any more trouble.
いつ 俺たちが
迷惑してるって言った？
When did we say anything
about you troubling us?
l'll feed you properly.
And l'll protect you from your pursuers.
ちゃんとした飯も作ってやる
追っ手からだって守ってやる
So stop worrying and
focus on getting better.
だから 心配せずに体を治せ
すまない
Thank you...
You don't have to worry.
Go ahead and sleep too.
（タンダ）心配しなくていいんだ
君も眠りなさい
この時期は 傷に効く薬草が
たくさん採れるんだ
This time of year, there are plenty of
herbs that are good for wounds.
This old lady and l have known
each other for twenty years.
このおばさんとは
20年来の古いつきあいでね
いつも こんなふうに
傷だらけになっちゃ―
She gets herself torn up like she
is now and ends up at my door.
ここに転がり込んでくるんだ
Ever since we were children,
it's been one fight after another...
ガキのころから
斬った張ったを繰り返して―
...and l'd tend to
her injuries every time.
その度に 俺が傷を縫ってね
She's a woman, but her body's
covered in a patchwork of scars.
女のくせに体じゅう縫い痕だらけさ
そのおかげといっちゃ
なんだけど―
And thanks to that, l must say
l'm adept at stitching up wounds now...
傷を縫う腕が上がり
薬草にも やたらと詳しくなった
...and l've picked up quite a bit
about medicinal herbs too.
Has Balsa been a bodyguard
ever since she was a child?
バルサは そんな子供のころから
用心棒をしておるのか？
うん？ あっ いや…
Oh, no. When we were small,
she trained from sunup to sundown.
子供のうちは
修業に明け暮れていてね
用心棒稼業を始めたのは
６年ぐらい前かな
lt was about six years ago that she
started working as a bodyguard.
Has it already been that long?
（トーヤ）もう そんなになるかな
実は俺とサヤも バルサねえさんに
命を助けてもらったんだ
The truth is, Balsa saved
my life and Saya's too.
We're both orphans, so there aren't
any adults who look out for us.
俺たちは身よりもないから
守ってくれる大人なんていやしない
俺は サヤを
妹と思って育ててきたのに―
l've raised Saya as my sister,
but then slave traders tried to take her.
人買いどもが
サヤを取り上げようとしたのさ
そのときさ
バルサねえさんが助けてくれたのは
And that's when Balsa
showed up and saved the day.
短槍(たんそう)の さやすら抜かずに
あっという間に６人をのしちまった
Without even taking off
the sheath of her spear...
...she dispatched all six of them
in the blink of an eye.
まったく
このおばさんは 本当に強くてね
Really... She's a
powerful lady, this one...
She's put that strength to good use,
saving countless people.
そうやって
今まで何人もの命を救っているんだ
そのせいで
たくさんの命も奪ってきたけどね
And in the process,
l've also taken lots of lives.
You're awake, then?
起きてたのか
バルサ 大丈夫か？
Balsa! Are you all right?
No, not really. l'm aching all over.
ダメだね 痛いとこだらけさ
But l'll be better soon.
でも すぐ よくなるよ
（タンダ）
包帯と薬草を変える頃合いだ
lt's time to change your
bandages and salves.
Really, you heal amazingly
quickly for a middle-aged lady.
お前 中年とは思えん治りの早さだな
意外と早く動けそうかい？
（タンダ）そいつは無理だ
Will l be up and around
sooner than you thought?
Not a chance.
Even if the wound is closed...
傷が塞がったところで―
...the cut flesh and muscle
won't be good as new right away.
切れた肉や筋は すぐには
元どおりにはならないからな
あっ この傷は見覚えがあるぞ
l remember this scar!
This is the very first cut
that l ever stitched.
これは
俺が最初に縫ってやった傷だ
As l recall, you were crying
your eyes out at the time.
あんとき
お前ボロボロ泣いたっけな
Fool!
（バルサ）バカ やめな
くすぐったい
Stop it. That tickles!
あっ どうした？
What's the matter?
Something strange is
happening to my stomach.
何か おなかが おかしいのじゃ
なんだって！
What?
l've never seen such a prince!
You couldn't even tell you were hungry?
とんだ皇子様だね
おなかが すいたのも
分からなかったのかい？
これが
おなかが すくということか？
This is what hunger feels like?
How odd.
不思議じゃ
This tastes far better than
anything l ate at the palace.
宮で食べていたものより
ずっと おいしい
（トーヤ）そんなもんかね
You think so?
（バルサ）誰だ！
Who's there!
An egg... An egg...
卵 卵…
Mistress Torogai!
（バルサ）トロガイ師！
An egg...
（トロガイ）卵…
卵 卵 卵…
An egg... An egg...
An egg...
卵…
卵！
The egg!
As l sat huddled and alone, holding
back the tears on those nights...
When it felt like l was about
to succumb to my doubts...
...there you were,
at my side before l knew it.
lt was none other than you
who was there for me.
l keep wishing, "l want to be strong."
l stumble and hurt myself again.
But because l have you to believe in,
l can get back to my feet.
l simply want to tell
my dear one, "Thank you."
At the top of my lungs,
again and again.
l call out to my precious loved one.
ls my voice reaching you?
ln this world that always changes,
human warmth never does.
l'm certain l sensed the presence
of the one that l hold dear.
～♪
Next Time
That which resides within Chagum
is the egg of a spirit.
To unravel its mysteries, the door
to the Chamber of the Epistles opens.
Next time,
"Secret Plan, The Blue Hand."
Episode 5
Secret Plan, The Blue Hand
Balsa, can you break
the net that encircles you?